<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Steering Committee | CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</title>
	<atom:link href="/committee/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>The Civil Society 7 (C7) Group is one of the official Engagement Groups of the G7 and represents positions from the international civil society.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 07:25:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Mariko Kinai</title>
		<link>/committee/199/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[c7Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 04:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Steering Committee]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://civil7-org.check-xserver.jp/?p=199</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Mariko Kinai joined World Vision Japan (WVJ) in 2008 with over 21 years of professional experience which includes work for Japan Bank for International Cooperation (JBIC), the Japanese government financial aid organisation, and the University of Tokyo as senior academic staff, working for the President to establish a new multi-disciplinary academic alliance. In WVJ, she [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/committee/199/">Mariko Kinai</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mariko Kinai joined World Vision Japan (WVJ) in 2008 with over 21 years of professional experience which includes work for Japan Bank for International Cooperation (JBIC), the Japanese government financial aid organisation, and the University of Tokyo as senior academic staff, working for the President to establish a new multi-disciplinary academic alliance.</p>
<p>In WVJ, she assumed several responsibilities including response director of East Japan earthquake and tsunami, strategic and planning director, and the national director since 2017. </p>
<p>Beyond her role in World Vision Japan, Mariko also takes a part to contribute the civil sector and development field in Japan. She serves as a board member for Japan NGO Center for International Cooperation (JANIC) and Japan Non-Profit Organisation Centre (JNPOC). She is also a member of Advisory Committee for Evaluation in Japan International Cooperation Agency (JICA).  </p>
<p>Mariko has Master of Science (Msc) degree in development economics from Oxford University and Msc. in social policy and planning in developing countries from London School of Economics (LSE), and a member of Development Studies society in Japan. She is a part-time lecturer at Tokyo Institute of Technology University and Aoyama Gakuin University. </p>
<p>Mariko is a member of Hongo Church (Presbyterian) in Tokyo.<br />
She is a mother of eighteen years old son and a wife of Ei Kinai, a pediatrician. </p><p>The post <a href="/committee/199/">Mariko Kinai</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hiroki Matsubara</title>
		<link>/committee/197/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[c7Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 04:35:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Steering Committee]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://civil7-org.check-xserver.jp/?p=197</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Hiroki Matsubara is Executive Director of Hiroshima NPO Center (HNC) and Co-Chair of the Japan Civil Society Coalition on G7 Summit 2023. In HNC, he has been in charge of planning and coordination for the areas of Environment, Education, Sightseeing, Disaster Prevention, and Community Development. In this role, he works on supporting Japanese NPOs/NGOs, solving [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/committee/197/">Hiroki Matsubara</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hiroki Matsubara is Executive Director of Hiroshima NPO Center (HNC) and Co-Chair of the Japan Civil Society Coalition on G7 Summit 2023. In HNC, he has been in charge of planning and coordination for the areas of Environment, Education, Sightseeing, Disaster Prevention, and Community Development. In this role, he works on supporting Japanese NPOs/NGOs, solving local issues, advocacy, and collaboration to achieve the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs). Hiroki will organize the Citizen&#8217;s Summit for advocacy to the G7 Summit with multi-stakeholders in Hiroshima on 16-17 April 2023.</p><p>The post <a href="/committee/197/">Hiroki Matsubara</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Aoi Horiuchi</title>
		<link>/committee/195/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[c7Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 04:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Steering Committee]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://civil7-org.check-xserver.jp/?p=195</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Aoi Horiuchi is Senior Advocacy Officer of Japan NGO Center for International Cooperation (JANIC), as well as Deputy Director of THINK Lobby, and has been working on achieving Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), especially Goal 16 and protecting civic space in Japan and Asia. Aoi is an active member of Development Unit, Japan Civil Society Network [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/committee/195/">Aoi Horiuchi</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Aoi Horiuchi is Senior Advocacy Officer of Japan NGO Center for International Cooperation (JANIC), as well as Deputy Director of THINK Lobby, and has been working on achieving Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), especially Goal 16 and protecting civic space in Japan and Asia. Aoi is an active member of Development Unit, Japan Civil Society Network on SDGs, and has participated many international fora such as UN General Assembly, UN High-Level Political Forum, past G7 and G20 Summits etc., for advocacy purposes.<br />
Aoi served as co-secretariat for civil society platform on G7 Ise-Shima Summit in 2016, and C20 Sous-Sherpa in 2019 when the Government of Japan hosted G20 Osaka Summit.</p><p>The post <a href="/committee/195/">Aoi Horiuchi</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Anke Kurat</title>
		<link>/committee/193/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[c7Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 04:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Steering Committee]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://civil7-org.check-xserver.jp/?p=193</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Anke Kurat studied regional sciences of Latin America as well as political science, Spanish and French at the University of Cologne and in Lisbon. Since 2002 she has been a political advisor at the Association of German Development and Humanitarian Aid NGOs. Since 2019 she is heading the Global Justice and Sustainable Development department. Previously, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/committee/193/">Anke Kurat</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Anke Kurat studied regional sciences of Latin America as well as political science, Spanish and French at the University of Cologne and in Lisbon. Since 2002 she has been a political advisor at the Association of German Development and Humanitarian Aid NGOs. Since 2019 she is heading the Global Justice and Sustainable Development department. Previously, she was responsible for the foreign projects in Chile and northeastern Brazil at Kindernothilfe in Duisburg. At the German Red Cross she was responsible for personnel recruitment and deployment to the Balkans and Latin America.</p><p>The post <a href="/committee/193/">Anke Kurat</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jürgen Maier</title>
		<link>/committee/191/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[c7Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 04:34:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Steering Committee]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://civil7-org.check-xserver.jp/?p=191</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Born 1963. Director of the German NGO Forum Environment &#38; Development since 1996. Organized The Other Economic Summit during the G7 Munich 1992. Member of the Civil Society Advisory Committee for the Russian G8 Presidency 2006, closely involved in C7 and C20 processes in Germany 2007, 2015, 2017, 2022 and in Japan 2008 and 2019, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/committee/191/">Jürgen Maier</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Born 1963. Director of the German NGO Forum Environment &amp; Development since 1996. Organized The Other Economic Summit during the G7 Munich 1992. Member of the Civil Society Advisory Committee for the Russian G8 Presidency 2006, closely involved in C7 and C20 processes in Germany 2007, 2015, 2017, 2022 and in Japan 2008 and 2019, Argentina 2018, Saudi Arabia 2020 and others.</p><p>The post <a href="/committee/191/">Jürgen Maier</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Valeria Emmi</title>
		<link>/committee/189/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[c7Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 04:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Steering Committee]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://civil7-org.check-xserver.jp/?p=189</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Valeria Emmi has been working as Networking and Advocacy Senior Specialist for CESVI (Italian NGO), currently leading the CESVI global advocacy at international, European and national level to support its effective integration in humanitarian and development programming. She represents CESVI in several coalition committees, both at national and international level, as in GCAP – Global [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/committee/189/">Valeria Emmi</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Valeria Emmi has been working as Networking and Advocacy Senior Specialist for <a href="https://www.cesvi.eu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CESVI</a> (Italian NGO), currently leading the CESVI global advocacy at international, European and national level to support its effective integration in humanitarian and development programming. She represents CESVI in several coalition committees, both at national and international level, as in <a href="https://gcap.global/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GCAP – Global Call to Action Against Poverty (Italy)</a> &#8211; a key interlocutor for Italian institutions on G7/G20 processes and the 2030 Agenda implementation, and expression of the largest global CS movement, calling for an end to poverty and inequality, promoting sustainable policies that respect human rights, gender equality, social and environmental justice, within the 2030 Agenda framework.</p>
<p>She currently serves as Co-Chair of the Advocacy and Communications Group of Alliance2015, a strategic partnership of 7 European NGOs which are engaged in humanitarian and development action.</p>
<p>In 2021, during the G20 Italian Presidency, she was appointed C20 Sous-Sherpa.</p>
<p>Valeria Emmi has a sound experience in designing and managing advocacy strategy development, policy dialogue with decision-makers in politics and galvanising donors&#8217; support on different policy issues such as food and nutrition security, community resilience building and climate change (DRR), mixed-migration and protection, and increasingly specialising in women’s empowerment to tackle poverty and inequality in all its forms. Economist with a wide experience in research coordination, she has also authored various publications for an effective and evidence-based advocacy.</p><p>The post <a href="/committee/189/">Valeria Emmi</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Carelle Mang-Benza</title>
		<link>/committee/187/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[c7Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 04:33:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Steering Committee]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://civil7-org.check-xserver.jp/?p=187</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Carelle Mang-Benza is the Policy Lead at Cooperation Canada. Her responsibilities include examining trends in international development and humanitarian work, developing advocacy and collaboration strategies in the sector, and advancing dialogue with Global Affairs Canada and members of Parliament. Before joining Cooperation Canada in November 2021, Carelle accumulated 20 years of experience working in climate [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/committee/187/">Carelle Mang-Benza</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Carelle Mang-Benza is the Policy Lead at Cooperation Canada. Her responsibilities include examining trends in international development and humanitarian work, developing advocacy and collaboration strategies in the sector, and advancing dialogue with Global Affairs Canada and members of Parliament. Before joining Cooperation Canada in November 2021, Carelle accumulated 20 years of experience working in climate change mitigation and adaptation at the United Nations as well as environmental policy and humanitarian assistance with the US State Department in West and Central Africa. Carelle holds Ph.D. in geography and environment from the University of Western Ontario and a M.Sc. in chemical engineering from Universite Laval in Quebec City.</p><p>The post <a href="/committee/187/">Carelle Mang-Benza</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ben Bestor</title>
		<link>/committee/185/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[c7Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 04:33:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Steering Committee]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://civil7-org.check-xserver.jp/?p=185</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ben Bestor is a senior program coordinator on the Global Development Policy and Learning team at InterAction. In this role, he coordinates the G7/G20 Advocacy Alliance, a group of US-based CSOs that work together to influence the annual G7 and G20 summits. Ben also manages InterAction’s Evaluation and Program Effectiveness Community of Practice and supports [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/committee/185/">Ben Bestor</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ben Bestor is a senior program coordinator on the Global Development Policy and Learning team at InterAction. In this role, he coordinates the G7/G20 Advocacy Alliance, a group of US-based CSOs that work together to influence the annual G7 and G20 summits. Ben also manages InterAction’s Evaluation and Program Effectiveness Community of Practice and supports the Children and Youth Initiative and the </span><a href="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">NGO Aid Map</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><p>The post <a href="/committee/185/">Ben Bestor</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sandra Martinsone</title>
		<link>/committee/183/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[c7Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 04:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Steering Committee]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://civil7-org.check-xserver.jp/?p=183</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Sandra Martinsone is Policy Manager on Sustainable Economic Development at Bond UK. She has 20 years of experience working for humanitarian and international development organisations. For the last 1 years Sandra has focused on research, policy and advocacy specialising in political economy, tax justice, ethical trade, development finance institutions, decolonisation of economic development and food [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/committee/183/">Sandra Martinsone</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sandra Martinsone is Policy Manager on Sustainable Economic Development at Bond UK. She has 20 years of experience working for humanitarian and international development organisations. For the last 1 years Sandra has focused on research, policy and advocacy specialising in political economy, tax justice, ethical trade, development finance institutions, decolonisation of economic development and food systems. She also has previously worked for UNDP, Foreign office in Latvia and has MA in International Political Economy from University of Leeds, UK.</p><p>The post <a href="/committee/183/">Sandra Martinsone</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jamila Asanova</title>
		<link>/committee/181/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[c7Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 04:32:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Steering Committee]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://civil7-org.check-xserver.jp/?p=181</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ms. Jamila Asanova has over 30 years experience in the development sector. As the CEO of ARGO, Ms. Asanova has expanded the umbrella organization to cover 8 Central Asian regional countries with 2,000+ member organizations and activists; managed multi-million USD regional projects; and developed ARGO to a staff of 50 personnel throughout the region. She [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/committee/181/">Jamila Asanova</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ms. Jamila Asanova has over 30 years experience in the development sector. As the CEO of ARGO, Ms. Asanova has expanded the umbrella organization to cover 8 Central Asian regional countries with 2,000+ member organizations and activists; managed multi-million USD regional projects; and developed ARGO to a staff of 50 personnel throughout the region. She was the steward of the I4C global governance board, uniting 7 Global South regional civil society development Hubs. Ms. Asanova is high-level advocate both within Kazakhstan and internationally, through membership in various national councils under the Ministries of Kazakhstan; and the first representative of Kazakhstani civil society to speak at the UN High Level Political Forum, in 2019. Ms. Asanova is a Chair of the Steering Committee of the Asia development Alliance, in 2022-2024.</p><p>The post <a href="/committee/181/">Jamila Asanova</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
