<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>News | CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</title>
	<atom:link href="/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>The Civil Society 7 (C7) Group is one of the official Engagement Groups of the G7 and represents positions from the international civil society.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 05:59:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Join us for the C7 Handover Event on 21 November 2023</title>
		<link>/news/1561/</link>
					<comments>/news/1561/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[c7Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 05:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1561</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The G7 Hiroshima Summit is almost over, though we still have two more Ministerial Meetings, Trade Ministers’ Meeting this weekend in Osaka, and Interior and Security Ministers’ Meeting in December, in Mito, and the new presidency is around the corner. We, Civil7, are also handing over the process from Japan to Italy, and you are [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/news/1561/">Join us for the C7 Handover Event on 21 November 2023</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1562" src="/wpC7/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/231121-C7-Handover-Event-with-QR.png" alt="C7 Handover Event on 21 November 2023" width="2560" height="1440" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/231121-C7-Handover-Event-with-QR.png 2560w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/231121-C7-Handover-Event-with-QR-300x169.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/231121-C7-Handover-Event-with-QR-1024x576.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/231121-C7-Handover-Event-with-QR-768x432.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/231121-C7-Handover-Event-with-QR-1536x864.png 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/231121-C7-Handover-Event-with-QR-2048x1152.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></div>
<div></div>
<div class="">The G7 Hiroshima Summit is almost over, though we still have two more Ministerial Meetings, Trade Ministers’ Meeting this weekend in Osaka, and Interior and Security Ministers’ Meeting in December, in Mito, and the new presidency is around the corner.</div>
<div class=""></div>
<div class="">We, Civil7, are also handing over the process from Japan to Italy, and you are all invited to join the C7 official hand over event on 21 November in Rome, Italy, and virtually.</div>
<div class=""></div>
<p>We will share reflections and challenges of C7 activities, and representatives of the C7 Working Groups will speak about what were effective and what can be improved for policy advocacy. We will also announce some updates for C7 2024.</p>
<div class=""></div>
<div class="">Please register through the link below.</div>
<div class=""><a class="" href="https://forms.gle/BckYAn368j1QMWft6">https://forms.gle/BckYAn368j1QMWft6</a></div>
<div></div>
<p><span id="more-1561"></span></p>
<div>
<div class=""><strong>Date</strong>: Tuesday 21, November 2023<br class="" /><strong>Time</strong>: 08:30-10:30 EST / 14:30-16:30 CET / 22:30-24:30 JST<br class="" /><strong>Format</strong>: Hybrid<br class="" /><strong>Place</strong>: Save the Children Italia office (Piazza di San Francesco di Paola, 9, 00184 Roma, Italy)</div>
<div class=""><strong>Organiser</strong>: C7 2023<br class="" /><strong>Registration</strong>: <a class="" href="https://forms.gle/BckYAn368j1QMWft6">https://forms.gle/BckYAn368j1QMWft6</a></div>
<div class=""><br class="" /><strong>Objectives</strong>:</div>
<div class="">-To understand the C7 process in order to prepare for 2024<br class="" />-To reflect achievements and challenges of activities by C7 2023 and share among participants<br class="" />-To demonstrate partnership and collaboration among C7 colleagues<br class="" /><br class="" /><strong>Programs (all time in CET)</strong>:</div>
<div class=""><strong>14:30-14:35</strong> Welcome and Opening Remarks<br class="" />            &#8211;<strong>Valeria Emmi</strong>, GCAP Italy, CESVI / C7 Steering Committee<br class="" /><br class="" /><strong>14:35-14:50</strong> Overall Reflection and Challenges of C7 activities in 2023<br class="" />            &#8211;<strong>Aoi Horiuchi</strong>, JANIC / C7 Steering Committee<br class="" /><br class="" /><strong>14:50-15:05</strong> C7 Monitoring and Evaluation: Key Findings<br class="" />            &#8211;<strong>Kamaladevy Sivalingam</strong>, Play for Change<br class="" /><br class="" /><strong>15:05-16:15</strong> Policy Recommendations and Reflections by C7 Working Groups<br class="" />            -Moderator: <strong>Darron Seller-Peritz</strong>, Cooperation Canada<br class="" />            -Speakers:<br class="" /><br class="" />             (tbc) , C7 Nuclear Disarmament Working Group<br class="" />             <strong>Risa Endo</strong>, C7 Climate and Environmental Justice Working Group<br class="" />             <strong>Shoko Uchida</strong>, C7 Economic Justice and Transformation Working Group<br class="" />             <strong>Masaki Inaba</strong>, C7 Global Health Working Group<br class="" />             <strong>Yuko Shibata</strong>, C7 Humanitarian Assistance and Conflict Working Group<br class="" />             <strong>Narayan Adhikari</strong>, C7 Open and Resilient Societies Working Group<br class="" /><br class="" />             Followed by Q&amp;A<br class="" /><br class="" />16:15-16:20 Announcement for the C7 2024 (C7 Steering Committee, Working Groups, Timelines etc.)<br class="" /><br class="" />16:20-16:25 Official hand over ceremony from C7 Japan to C7 Italy<br class="" />            &#8211;<strong>Aoi Horiuchi</strong>, JANIC / C7 Steering Committee<br class="" />            &#8211;<strong>Riccardo Moro</strong>, GCAP Italy<br class="" /><br class="" />16:25-16:30 Closing Remarks<br class="" />            &#8211;<strong>Mariko Kinai</strong> and <strong>Hiroki Matsubara</strong> / C7 2023 Steering Committee (online)</div>
<div class=""></div>
<div class="">Contact: <strong>Civil7 Secretariat</strong> &lt;<a class="" href="mailto:info@civil7.org">info@civil7.org</a>&gt;</div>
</div><p>The post <a href="/news/1561/">Join us for the C7 Handover Event on 21 November 2023</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/news/1561/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Citizens’ Declaration on Peace 2023</title>
		<link>/news/1282/</link>
					<comments>/news/1282/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[c7Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 05:42:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1282</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Together with Citizens’ Summit 2023, C7 (Civil) published Citizens’ Declaration on Peace 2023 on 6 August, 78 years after the atomic bombing in Hiroshima. A press conference was held to explain the declaration and show CSOs&#8217; willingness to engage with advocacy works to G7 governments and beyond. &#8220;We have been disappointed to the outcome document [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/news/1282/">Citizens’ Declaration on Peace 2023</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Together with <strong>Citizens’ Summit 2023</strong>, <strong>C7 (Civil)</strong> published <strong>Citizens’ Declaration on Peace 2023</strong> on <strong>6 August</strong>, 78 years after the atomic bombing in Hiroshima. A press conference was held to explain the declaration and show CSOs&#8217; willingness to engage with advocacy works to G7 governments and beyond.</p>
<p>&#8220;<em>We have been disappointed to the outcome document of the G7 Leaders Summit in Hiroshima back in May 2023, on climate crisis, global health, economic inequality, humanitarian assistance, civic space and human rights, and especially nuclear disarmament. We will continue our advocacy on key development issues and peace towards G7 leaders, in 2024, when the Government of Italy will host the next G7 Summit in June</em>&#8220;, said <strong>Aoi Horiuchi</strong>, Steering Committee of C7.</p>
<p>&#8220;<em>Prime Minister Fumio Kishida&#8217;s remarks at the Peace Memorial Ceremony showed no strong desire or concrete plan for the abolition of nuclear weapons. The &#8220;Hiroshima Vision&#8221; adopted at the G7 Summit justifies nuclear deterrence head-on in a city that appeals to nuclear abolition as its only hope</em>&#8220;, said <strong>Setsuko Thurlow</strong>, a Hibakusha (atomic bomb survivor) and a leading figure in the International Campaign to Abolish Nuclear Weapons (ICAN).</p>
<p><strong>Akira Kawasaki</strong>, International Steering Group of ICAN and Executive Committee member of Peaceboat said, &#8220;<em>the G7 has not created a timeline for nuclear abolition. We will encourage the government through a campaign for nuclear abolition in Japan</em>&#8220;.</p>
<p><strong>Tomoko Watanabe</strong>, Chair of ANT-Hiroshima, concluded that &#8220;<em>Hiroshima was turned into a rental seat at the G7 summit. We will reclaim Hiroshima. We will think again, connect, gain strength, and act again</em>&#8220;.</p>
<p>The press conference was held in Hiroshima NPO Center office at 10:00-12:00, on 6 August 2023, moderated by <strong>Hiroki Matsubara</strong>, Executive Director of Hiroshima NPO Center, as well as Steering Committee of C7.</p>
<p>Please refer to the statement (PDF) from <a href="/wpC7/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Citizens-Peace-Declaration-2023.pdf">here</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1284" src="/wpC7/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/IMG_1944.jpg" alt="" width="2016" height="1512" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/IMG_1944.jpg 2016w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/IMG_1944-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/IMG_1944-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/IMG_1944-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/IMG_1944-1536x1152.jpg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 2016px) 100vw, 2016px" /></p>
<hr />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Citizens’ Declaration on Peace 2023</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: right;">6 August 2023<br />
Citizens’ Summit 2023<br />
C7 (Civil)</p>
<p>This &#8220;Citizens Declaration on Peace 2023&#8221; is addressed by civil society organizations in and beyond Japan to appeal to world leaders and citizens to reconsider peace in light of the experience of the G7 Hiroshima Summit, and to realize it together.</p>
<p>We call on the G7 and other world leaders to make decisions and take action to ABOLISH nuclear weapons.</p>
<p>This year, the G7 Hiroshima Summit was held in Japan. In solidarity with a national and international civil society, we organized the Citizen’s Summit 2023 in Hiroshima in April. To tackle various social issues, including nuclear disarmament, climate change, conflict, inequality, gender, people with disabilities, childcare, youth, SDGs, public procurement, history of Hiroshima, disaster prevention, and the direction of the G7, we held discussions among citizens from various backgrounds. In addition, at the C7 (Civil7), one of the official engagement groups of the G7 process, we established six working groups with over 700 civil society representatives from 72 countries, including on nuclear disarmament, to engage in dialogue and to make policy recommendations to the G7.</p>
<p>However, the G7 Leaders&#8217; Hiroshima Vision on Nuclear Disarmament issued by the G7 leaders was not what we &#8211; the citizens and Hibakusha, atomic bomb survivors, &#8211; expected, and we have to express our great disappointment and dismay. It might be premature to evaluate the G7 Hiroshima Summit at this point. It should also be noted that the variety of opinions on the evaluation of the Summit could be seen as a reflection of the civil society’s diversity, which we value. However, it was clear from the G7 Hiroshima Summit that the G7 leaders do not aim at the abolition of nuclear weapons, and they discussed the arms transfer rather than a ceasefire between Ukraine and Russia. In addition, seven organisations of Hiroshima Hibakusha have expressed regret that the bag containing the device that commands a nuclear attack, the &#8220;nuclear button&#8221;, was unabashedly brought into Hiroshima Peace Memorial Park, saying that this is a desecration and insult to the A- bombed city that tramples on the memorials of the A-bomb victims and their wish for nuclear weapons abolition.</p>
<p>It must be said that citizens are excluded from the democratic process and the will of the A-bomb survivors is neglected. Furthermore, in June, a sister park agreement between Hiroshima Peace Memorial Park and Pearl Harbor National Memorial was signed solely and hastily by the administrative decision, and many citizens do not understand this process and information. This is a crisis for the peace administration as the A-bombed city of Hiroshima.</p>
<p>As a result of these, the process of nuclear weapons abolition has regressed, and as citizens who have long appealed for the early abolition of nuclear weapons, we cannot accept the current situation. We continue to call on the Japanese Government and the nuclear-armed states to create a vision from nuclear disarmament to nuclear abolition and to sign and ratify the Prohibition of Nuclear Weapons (TPNW). And civil society will continue to be willing to engage in dialogue and policy cooperation with governments in order to realize a “sustainable society without nuclear weapons and leaving no one behind.”</p>
<p>Here, we would like to think and act together with all citizens of the world. Let us look at peace not only in the distance but also around us, redefine the peace we want, and act to achieve it.</p>
<p>While we hope for the abolition of nuclear weapons, nine states in the world possess nuclear weapons and there are an estimated 12,705 warheads on the planet. And the reality is that many countries including Japan are under the nuclear umbrella of the United States and others. In addition, nuclear weapons are not merely a security issue, but also complex and serious problems,<br />
as citizens are living with nuclear threats, such as being actually affected by nuclear testing or nuclear power plant accidents all over the world.</p>
<p>Before the Leaders’ Summit, we, as C7, officially made the policy recommendations to the G7 on nuclear disarmament, climate and environmental justice, economic justice and transformation, global health, humanitarian assistance and conflict, and open and resilient society. Unfortunately, nevertheless, the G7 Hiroshima Summit Declaration did not incorporate many of the perspectives of civil society and was not something that citizens could appreciate. From a different perspective, it was an opportunity to reflect on the fact that civil society is still immature and is not yet fully equipped with the power and methods to improve our society. We have determined to improve and repeatedly build on this process. That is why the first step we propose is to redefine the citizens&#8217; idea of &#8216;peace&#8217; once again.</p>
<p>After 78 years since the atomic bombings, we wonder if the peace proclaimed by the Prime Ministers and mayors at the Peace Memorial Ceremony in Hiroshima and Nagasaki truly represents the voice of citizens. Let us think, speak out, and act together on what kind of peace we, as citizens, hope for, and what are needed to realize it.</p>
<p>We hope that this message will reach the leaders of the G7 and other countries, as well as citizens around the world, in order to create a sustainable society without nuclear weapons, where no one is left behind, with our own hands.</p>
<p><strong>References:</strong><br />
Citizens’ Summit 2023<br />
<a href="https://hiroshimacsummit2023.mystrikingly.com/">https://hiroshimacsummit2023.mystrikingly.com/</a><br />
Civil7 2023 JAPAN<br />
<a href="/">/</a><br />
C7 Communiqué 2023<br />
/wpC7/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/C7_communique2023_0412.pdf<br />
G7 Hiroshima Leaders’ Communiqué<br />
https://www.mofa.go.jp/files/100506878.pdf<br />
G7 Leaders’ Hiroshima Vision on Nuclear Disarmament<br />
https://www.mofa.go.jp/dns/ac_d/page1e_000679.html</p>
<p><strong>Contact:</strong><br />
Hiroki Matsubara, Co-organizer, Citizens’ Summit 2023, matsubara@npoc.or.jp<br />
Aoi Horiuchi, Steering Committee, Civil7, info@civil7.org</p><p>The post <a href="/news/1282/">Citizens’ Declaration on Peace 2023</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/news/1282/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Women as Key Players in Development &#8211; Open dialogue with G7 &#038; G20 stakeholders</title>
		<link>/news/994/</link>
					<comments>/news/994/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[c7Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 02:01:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=994</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>During the UN High-Level Political Forum (HLPF) in 2023, there will be an event &#8220;Women as Key Players in Development &#8211; Open dialogue with G7 &#38; G20 stakeholders&#8221; to be held on 11 July by Women’s Major Group. It will aim to open up a space for dialogue between G7 &#38; G20 member states, W20, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/news/994/">Women as Key Players in Development – Open dialogue with G7 & G20 stakeholders</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>During the UN High-Level Political Forum (HLPF) in 2023, there will be an event <strong>&#8220;Women as Key Players in Development &#8211; Open dialogue with G7 &amp; G20 stakeholders&#8221;</strong> to be held on 11 July by Women’s Major Group.</p>
<p>It will aim to open up a space for dialogue between G7 &amp; G20 member states, W20, C20 and W7 engagement groups and the WMG on our priorities and main messages towards HLPF &amp; the SDG Summit, with regards to gender equality, women in development and women’s human rights. The details are as follows:</p>
<p><strong>■ Date:</strong> 11 July 2023<br />
<strong>■ Time:</strong> 9:30 to 10:30am<br />
<strong>■ Venue:</strong> UN Church Center 2nd Floor</p>
<p>In order to participate, please RSVP through this link:<br />
<a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSd921QPe0O3fMIi2F6k0jSfjb_VjQTDXYucAkjuBzPOSlIjog/viewform">https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSd921QPe0O3fMIi2F6k0jSfjb_VjQTDXYucAkjuBzPOSlIjog/viewform</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-995" src="/wpC7/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/C20-poster-1-1.png" alt="" width="640" height="360" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/C20-poster-1-1.png 640w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/07/C20-poster-1-1-300x169.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></p><p>The post <a href="/news/994/">Women as Key Players in Development – Open dialogue with G7 & G20 stakeholders</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/news/994/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Webinar on Civic Engagement with G7-BRICS-G20 Summits</title>
		<link>/news/957/</link>
					<comments>/news/957/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[c7Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 09:36:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=957</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The PEOPLES’ 20 webinar on Civic Engagement with G7-BRICS-G20 Summits will be held on Thursday, 29 June 2023, at 2 PM (London) 6:30 PM (New Delhi) 8 PM (Bangkok) 10:00 PM (Seoul and Tokyo). One of the coordinators of the C7 Global Health Working Group, Masaki Inaba, will be speaking at the webinar. Webinar on [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/news/957/">Webinar on Civic Engagement with G7-BRICS-G20 Summits</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The PEOPLES’ 20 webinar on Civic Engagement with G7-BRICS-G20 Summits will be held on Thursday, 29 June 2023, at 2 PM (London) 6:30 PM (New Delhi) 8 PM (Bangkok) 10:00 PM (Seoul and Tokyo). One of the coordinators of the C7 Global Health Working Group, Masaki Inaba, will be speaking at the webinar.</p>
<hr />
<h3 style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #0000ff;"><strong>Webinar on Civic Engagement with G7-BRICS-G20 Summits<br />
</strong></span><strong>29 June 2023 (Thursday)</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Zoom: <a href="https://bit.ly/3InGsSp">https://bit.ly/3InGsSp</a></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">The webinar, jointly organized by PEOPOES’ 20, AEPF and POP Dialogue aims to address the challenges, foster a common understanding, and formulate effective advocacy strategies pertaining to the triple annual ‘geopolitical’ summits, namely G7, BRICS and G20 among CSOs in Asia and Europe.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">This is a follow-up to the virtual session on Nexus Approach to G7-BRICS-G20 at the PyeongChang-Odaesan-Peace (POP) Global Forum (8 Feb. 2023) <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=O97kjAmEJ_U&amp;t=6s">(115) G20, G7, BRICS versusInclusive Multilateralism &#8211; Jomo Kwame Sundaram &#8211; YouTube</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Guiding questions:</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Taking into account the PPT presentation by Jomo Sundaram, please respond to the following questions based on your experiences (2-3 minutes per question per person)</p>
<ol style="text-align: left;">
<li>What are emerging geopolitical challenges from G7, G20 and BRICS Summits in terms of global CSO advocacy for peace, justice and equality?</li>
<li>What is your critical assessment of the CSO engagement and advocacy so far with them &#8211; G7, BRICS and G20 Summits? What are the challenges facing the CSOs?</li>
<li>What are your suggestions for effective strategies among CSOs in Asia and Europe in terms of international advocacy strategies?</li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Contact:</strong> Peoples20G20Summit@gmail.com</p>
<p><strong>Time Zone: </strong>2 PM (London), 6:30 PM (New Delhi) 8 PM (Bangkok), 10:00 PM (Seoul and Tokyo)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Program Agenda and Timeline:</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-958 alignnone" src="/wpC7/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image-4.png" alt="" width="802" height="523" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image-4.png 802w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image-4-300x196.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image-4-768x501.png 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 802px) 100vw, 802px" /></p><p>The post <a href="/news/957/">Webinar on Civic Engagement with G7-BRICS-G20 Summits</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/news/957/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>[Activity Report] Recordings available &#8211; C7 Press Conferences during the G7 Hiroshima Summit</title>
		<link>/news/953/</link>
					<comments>/news/953/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[c7Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 08:18:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=953</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>During the G7 Hiroshima Summit in 2023, Civil7 organized eight press conferences, five of whose recordings are now available. Joint Press Conference by the G7 Engagement Groups (18 May 2023) https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8mhSsJGSWpE C7 Press Conference: Economic Justice and Transformation / Global Health (19 May 2023) https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FXkPykkxAR0 C7 Press Conference: Climate and Environmental Justice / Open and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/news/953/">[Activity Report] Recordings available – C7 Press Conferences during the G7 Hiroshima Summit</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>During the G7 Hiroshima Summit in 2023, Civil7 organized eight press conferences, five of whose recordings are now available.</p>
<p>Joint Press Conference by the G7 Engagement Groups (18 May 2023)<br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8mhSsJGSWpE">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8mhSsJGSWpE</a></p>
<p>C7 Press Conference: Economic Justice and Transformation / Global Health (19 May 2023)<br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FXkPykkxAR0">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FXkPykkxAR0</a></p>
<p>C7 Press Conference: Climate and Environmental Justice / Open and Resilient Societies (20 May 2023)<br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8_Wp5Hchf-A&amp;t=2s">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8_Wp5Hchf-A&amp;t=2s</a></p>
<p>C7 Press Conference: Evaluation on the G7 Leaders&#8217; Summit (21 May 2023)<br />
(Japanese) <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=57py6OvEzGY&amp;t=82s">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=57py6OvEzGY&amp;t=82s</a><br />
(English) <a href="https://youtu.be/aWaNQWAswKc">https://youtu.be/aWaNQWAswKc</a></p><p>The post <a href="/news/953/">[Activity Report] Recordings available – C7 Press Conferences during the G7 Hiroshima Summit</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/news/953/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>G7 Gender Equality Ministers and Civil Society Dialogue</title>
		<link>/news/947/</link>
					<comments>/news/947/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[c7Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 07:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=947</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>G7 Gender Equality Ministers and Civil Society Dialogue Monday, June 26, 16:30-19:00 JST/ 9:30-12:00 CEST Registration: https://us06web.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_3q7sXMvsRLu15K9VWTTQqw (Online participation only) As a follow-up to the G7 Ministerial Meeting on Gender Equality and Women’s Empowerment in Nikko on 24th and 25th June 2023, the W7 Japan would like to create a space for dialogue between the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/news/947/">G7 Gender Equality Ministers and Civil Society Dialogue</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3><span style="color: #0000ff;"><strong>G7 Gender Equality Ministers and Civil Society Dialogue</strong></span></h3>
<p><strong>Monday, June 26, 16:30-19:00 JST/ 9:30-12:00 CEST</strong></p>
<p><strong>Registration: <a href="https://us06web.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_3q7sXMvsRLu15K9VWTTQqw">https://us06web.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_3q7sXMvsRLu15K9VWTTQqw</a></strong><br />
(Online participation only)</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-948" src="/wpC7/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/x.png" alt="" width="497" height="500" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/x.png 497w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/06/x-298x300.png 298w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 497px) 100vw, 497px" /></p>
<p>As a follow-up to the G7 Ministerial Meeting on Gender Equality and Women’s Empowerment in Nikko on 24th and 25th June 2023, the W7 Japan would like to create a space for dialogue between the G7 Ministers on Gender Equality or their Representatives and the Civil Society, on gender equality, women’s leadership and human rights.</p>
<p>This will cover issues such as care economy, eradication of violence and bodily autonomy, digital world, LGBTQI+ and accountability.</p>
<p>The purpose of this Dialogue is to discuss the outcomes of the Gender Equality Ministers’ Meeting with Civil Society, and to carry the momentum to the next G7 Presidency – Italy.</p>
<p>The meeting will be opened by remarks of the Japan State Minister on Gender Equality and Women’s Empowerment, Mr. Masanobu Ogura, and the EU Commissioner for Equality, Ms Helena Dalli, followed by speeches by other G7 Ministers/representatives, and civil society representatives.</p>
<p>*Please see the attached program for more details!</p>
<p><strong>Date/hour<br />
</strong>Monday, 26th June, 2023<br />
16:30h &#8211; 19:00 JST / 9.30 &#8211; 12.00 CEST</p>
<p><strong>Location<br />
</strong>ZOOM (Online)</p>
<p><strong>Languages<br />
</strong>English / Japanese (simultaneous interpretation); Japanese Sign Language Available / Notetaker Available.</p>
<p><strong>Hosts<br />
</strong>Delegation of European Union to Japan/ W7 Japan</p>
<p><strong>Supported by<br />
</strong>the Gender Equality Bureau, Cabinet Office, Japan</p>
<p>W7 is the G7’s official engagement group of feminist civil society promoting gender equality &amp; women’s rights. (W7 Secretariat &#8211; w7japan2023@gmail.com)</p>
<p>Program details: <a href="/wpC7/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/June-26-EUDEL-W7_Event-Program.pdf">June 26 EUDEL W7_Event Program</a></p><p>The post <a href="/news/947/">G7 Gender Equality Ministers and Civil Society Dialogue</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/news/947/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>[Civil7 Statement] G7 Engagement Groups Unite for Achieving Gender Equality and the SDGs</title>
		<link>/news/937/</link>
					<comments>/news/937/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[c7Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 05:46:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=937</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>C7 &#8211; P7 &#8211; T7 &#8211; W7 &#8211; Y7 Joint Statement Reigniting the 2030 Agenda: Achieving Gender Equality Now and For Future Generations Ahead of the G7 Gender Ministers’ Meeting, the Civil7 (C7), Pride7 (P7), Think7 (T7), Women7 (W7), and Youth7 (Y7) Engagement Groups released the Joint Statement ‘Reigniting the 2030 Agenda: Achieving Gender Equality [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/news/937/">[Civil7 Statement] G7 Engagement Groups Unite for Achieving Gender Equality and the SDGs</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4><span style="color: #0000ff;"><strong>C7 &#8211; P7 &#8211; T7 &#8211; W7 &#8211; Y7 Joint Statement</strong></span><br />
<span style="color: #0000ff;"><strong>Reigniting the 2030 Agenda: Achieving Gender Equality Now and For Future Generations</strong></span></h4>
<p>Ahead of the G7 Gender Ministers’ Meeting, the Civil7 (C7), Pride7 (P7), Think7 (T7), Women7 (W7), and Youth7 (Y7) Engagement Groups released the Joint Statement ‘Reigniting the 2030 Agenda: Achieving Gender Equality Now and For Future Generations’ in an unprecedented show of solidarity for gender equality as a key intersectional issue for achieving the SDGs at the G7 level. This Joint Statement was created through a collaborative process between representatives of the C7, P7, T7, W7, and Y7.</p>
<p>Achieving gender equality is key to building resilience and safeguarding the world against current and future crises. The Joint Statement urges G7 Leaders to take urgent and ambitious steps to achieve the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development with a broad focus beyond the indicators set forth in SDG 5: Gender Equality. Emphasis is given to expanding social protections, ratifying ILO conventions, committing to universal basic income, increasing investment in education and upskilling, launching a people-centered and gender-sensitive measurement of human wellbeing and socioeconomic and environmental prosperity to supplement GDP, and strengthening accountability mechanisms for G7 commitments.</p>
<p>Finally, in response to some of the new challenges in the world today and to ensure that gender equality can be achieved now and sustained for future generations, the Joint Statement advocates for timely action to address the following additions for a post-2030 Agenda:</p>
<ul>
<li>Gender Equality in Digital and Emerging Technologies</li>
<li>Gender Equality for All</li>
<li>Gender Equality in Addressing the Climate Crisis</li>
<li>Gender Equality Through Feminist Foreign Policy (FFP) and Peacebuilding</li>
<li>Equal and Affordable Global Health Access and Comprehensive Sexual and Reproductive Health and Rights</li>
<li>Gender Equality in Food and Nutritional Security and Supply Chain</li>
</ul>
<p>Please refer to the statement (PDF) from <a href="/wpC7/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Gender-Equality-Joint-Statement-Final-Draft-06082023.pdf"><strong>here</strong></a>.</p>
<hr />
<h4 style="text-align: center;"><strong><br />
C7 &#8211; P7 &#8211; T7 &#8211; W7 &#8211; Y7 Joint Statement<br />
</strong><strong>Reigniting the 2030 Agenda: Achieving Gender Equality Now and For Future Generations</strong></h4>
<p>We, the <strong>Civil7 (C7), Pride7 (P7), Think7 (T7), Women7 (W7), and Youth7 (Y7)</strong>, remind the G7 leaders of the immediate and long-term impacts of education and human capital losses dramatically deepened by the Covid-19 pandemic, with even more severe consequences in regions impacted by armed conflicts and exposed to natural disasters, including global warming. Following the G7 Leaders’ Summit in Hiroshima, we unanimously call upon the G7 Presidency of Japan to take robust initiative ahead of the 2023 United Nations general assembly meeting and to gather commitments from the G7 and beyond to achieve the 2030 Agenda, a whole-of-society and gender-responsive approach to innovative solutions, and a common strategy among G7 leaders for progress now and for future generations.</p>
<p>In light of the multiple challenges of the day, strong, resilient, and comprehensive civil society engagement is critical to achieve the 2030 Agenda. This means working across generations and genders, leaving no one behind and instead, ensuring that human rights and related international treaties and conventions, including CEDAW and its Optional Protocol, are respected as the cornerstone of inclusive communities. Achieving gender equality is key to building resilience and safeguarding our world against current and future crises, including climate change, sustainable peace, health equity, food security, supply chain, gaps in access to digital and emerging technologies, and ensuring social inclusion, human rights, and dignity for all.</p>
<p>We, <strong>the C7, P7, T7, W7, and Y7 Engagement Groups</strong>, stand united on the critical importance of achieving and sustaining gender equality in this G7 Joint Statement. We call for G7 Leaders to prioritize ambitious public policies and investments in developing social infrastructure to achieve gender equality, to build honest, strong, unequivocal and universal support of the 2030 Agenda, and to lay the foundations for a more sustainable and prosperous future for all.</p>
<p>We call for: 1) expanding social protection to protect workers and their families, especially women and including migrant workers and marginalized and underrepresented groups; 2) ratifying and effectively enforcing ILO conventions on freedom of association (87), collective bargaining (98), and sexual harassment in the workplace (190); 3) committing to universal basic income and pay transparency legislation; 4) increasing public investment in education, training and upskilling, and recruitment of health workers; and 5) launching an innovative people-centered and gender-sensitive measurement of human wellbeing and socioeconomic, and environmental prosperity to supplement gross domestic product (GDP), including a comprehensive and concise set of indicators focused on multidimensional wellbeing.</p>
<p>We call for strengthening accountability mechanisms for G7 commitments including the continued support and the expansion of the G7 Gender Equality Advisory Council (GEAC) and the G7 Dashboard on Gender Gaps in collaboration with the OECD and civil society, to provide accurate, timely, and gender-disaggregated data on progress toward gender equality. We call for the recognition and support of the G7/G20 dashboard introduced by T7 Japan.</p>
<p>Given the urgent and accelerating changes in our world and with a view towards achieving sustainable progress in gender equality both now and for future generations, we call for responsive and timely policymaking and the following additions for a post-2030 Agenda.</p>
<p><strong>Gender Equality in Digital and Emerging Technologies</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Engage a whole-of-society approach in establishing human rights-based AI regulations and ensure that existing gender discriminatory biases are not translated or amplified in AI systems. Commit to developing international guidelines on gendered hate speech and technology-facilitated gender-based violence (tfGBV) in line with the Rabat Plan of Action, CEDAW, Women Peace and Security agendas, and the Universal Declaration on Human Rights.</li>
<li>Transform education curricula to include gender-responsive digital skills and STEAM education from primary grades and expand meaningful mentorship programs between girls and women in STEAM. Ensure that women are skilled and competitive in the digital job market and support lifelong learning and labor mobility for women by funding gender-responsive public programs on digital literacy and skills, strengthening women’s digital talent pipeline and entrepreneurial capacity in FemTech.</li>
<li>Increase women’s access to gender-responsive digital healthcare services and financial products. Increase funding for online platforms providing critical information and aid to those suffering from domestic violence, sexual harassment, and mental illness.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Gender Equality for All</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fulfill commitments in the G7 Elmau Leaders&#8217; Declaration to ensure the full, equal, effective, and meaningful participation of LGBTQIA+ people in society; legalize same-sex marriage and enhance legal protection for same-sex partnerships and their families; and enact anti-discrimination laws to protect those of diverse SOGIESC with indicators tracking inclusion across a range of policy areas.</li>
<li>Ensure meaningful participation of all genders, with an intersectional approach, at every stage of decision and policy making processes at the national and international levels and allocate funding for civil society-led organizations and human rights activists that support the LGBTQIA+ community.</li>
<li>Fund programs supporting bodily autonomy and self-determination and increase funding to provide comprehensive SRHR, integrated GBV prevention and mitigation services, and protection of the rights of women and girls in all their diversity and persons of diverse SOGIESC.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Gender Equality in Addressing the Climate Crisis</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Strengthen climate adaptation capacities for vulnerable people and communities—women, youth, children, people with disabilities, Indigenous Peoples, the poor, elderly, rural communities, and others affected by marginalization and discrimination, and support access to a safe, livable world with clean air, water, sanitation, hygiene, food, health, and adequate housing.</li>
<li>Promote participation of women, youth, and other marginalized groups and communities in decision making on climate and environmental policies. Pursue gender-equal budgeting processes, allocation, and tax policies at all levels in international development policies.</li>
<li>Increase investment in jobs and skills for a low-carbon transition and expand inclusive, gender transformative climate education policies which foster knowledge, skills, attitudes, and behaviors that enable women and girls to engage in sustainable, safe, rewarding, and dignified work.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Gender Equality Through Feminist Foreign Policy (FFP) and Peacebuilding</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Work toward adopting and implementing feminist foreign policies that are coherent across all foreign policy areas, including diplomacy, security and defense, trade, humanitarian assistance and development, and ensure that their implementation remains accountable to feminist civil society.</li>
<li>FFPs must build on existing commitments, including full and effective implementation of UN human rights treaties, CEDAW and its Optional Protocol, the Women Peace and Security Agenda, Youth Peace and Security Agenda, and the Global Compact for Migration. They should affirm and increase funding for the four pillars of the Women, Peace and Security and Humanitarian Action Compact.</li>
<li>Ensure that 100% of bilateral allocable Official Development Assistance (ODA) funding integrates gender equality as a target. Secure at least 20% of ODA funding for programs with gender equality as the principal objective, and at least 10% directed at feminist and women-led NGOs, including locally led organizations.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Equal and Affordable Global Health Access and Comprehensive Sexual and Reproductive Health and Rights</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Deliver on past international agreements on comprehensive sexual and reproductive health and rights (SRHR), stop Gender-Based Violence (GBV) with robust measures to end impunity and guarantee access to redress, and set a 10-year International Women and Girls Health Action Plan to Eliminate the Gender Health Gap with targets, funding, and full inclusion of women at every stage of the decision-making process.</li>
<li>Increase funding for SRHR campaigns and advocacy to ensure access to menstrual hygiene products, contraceptives, including low-dose pills and emergency contraceptives, safe abortions, essential information about SRHR, menstrual health and gynecologic diseases, inclusive of trans and non-binary people, and dismantle social stigmas.</li>
<li>Legislate and subsidize flexible care and parental leave options to achieve a more inclusive work environment for all parents and families based on a recognition of care as public good, and reward unpaid work/care starting with reviewing the impact of care work by gender disaggregated data.</li>
<li>Enhance global cooperation and partnerships to support pregnant women worldwide by providing sufficient nutritious resources, comprehensive health education, and maximize the global social impact of dismantling harmful stigmas, including body size stereotyping, that contribute to restricted access to safe perinatal care and nutritious food.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Gender Equality in Food and Nutritional Security and Supply Chain</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Ensure a just and inclusive transition to sustainable food systems and the right to healthy and climate-friendly diets by fostering agro-ecological systems with a focus on small-scale farmers and women, stop harmful subsidies, and seek to end hunger and malnutrition, while ensuring human rights of laborers and women’s equal access to land and property rights.</li>
<li>Increase funding for and invest in women in rural development, provide support to build skills, and facilitate access to markets, resources, assets, credit, and crop and livestock diversification and expand and invest in affordable AI technology and digital advisory services in agriculture, with gender-sensitive training for women, to improve the wellbeing of smallholder farmers and food and nutritional security, as women make up a significant portion of the agricultural labor force.</li>
</ul><p>The post <a href="/news/937/">[Civil7 Statement] G7 Engagement Groups Unite for Achieving Gender Equality and the SDGs</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/news/937/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Virtual Bangkok Forum on G20 Summit</title>
		<link>/news/987/</link>
					<comments>/news/987/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[c7Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 01:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=987</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Virtual Bangkok Forum on G20 Summit Date: Monday, 5 June 2023 Time: 22:00-23:30 (JST) / 24:00-25:30 (JST) Modality: Zoom meeting https://us06web.zoom.us/j/87273739472?pwd=VUxrT1pwdEdoRWxkdGxYZ0xSclU1dz09 Meeting ID: 872 7373 9472　　Passcode: 175457 Program: Webinar 1（22:00-23:30） Moderator: Anselmo Lee, Asia Civil Society Partnership for Sustainable Development (APSD), Korea / Peoples&#8217; 20 Co-convener -Welcome Remarks: Francesco Aureli, GCAP Italy / Peoples&#8217; 20 [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/news/987/">Virtual Bangkok Forum on G20 Summit</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="color: #0000ff;"><strong>Virtual Bangkok Forum on G20 Summit</strong></span></p>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Monday, 5 June 2023</p>
<p><strong>Time:</strong> 22:00-23:30 (JST) / 24:00-25:30 (JST)</p>
<p><strong>Modality:</strong> Zoom meeting<br />
https://us06web.zoom.us/j/87273739472?pwd=VUxrT1pwdEdoRWxkdGxYZ0xSclU1dz09<br />
Meeting ID: 872 7373 9472　　Passcode: 175457</p>
<p><strong>Program:</strong></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Webinar 1（22:00-23:30）</span><br />
Moderator: Anselmo Lee, Asia Civil Society Partnership for Sustainable Development (APSD), Korea / Peoples&#8217; 20 Co-convener</p>
<p>-Welcome Remarks: Francesco Aureli, GCAP Italy / Peoples&#8217; 20 Co-convener-Presentation of the Working Documents: Vidya Dinker, India Social Action Forum / Peoples&#8217; 20 Co-convener<br />
-Q and A, Comments<br />
-Wrap-up and Closing Remarks: Co-conveners</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Webinar 2（24:00-25:30）</span><br />
Moderator: Aoi Horiuchi, Japan NGO Center for International Cooperation (JANIC) / C7 2023 Steering Committee / Peoples&#8217; 20 Co-convener</p>
<p>-Welcome Remarks: Netra Timsina, LDC Watch / Peoples&#8217; 20 Co-convener<br />
-Presentation of the Working Documents: Annie Namala, Wada Na Todo Abhiyan (WNTA) / Peoples&#8217; 20 Co-convener<br />
-Q and A, Comments<br />
-Wrap-up and Closing Remarks: Co-conveners</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-988" src="/wpC7/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image-19.png" alt="" width="900" height="900" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image-19.png 900w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image-19-300x300.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image-19-768x768.png 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 900px) 100vw, 900px" /></p><p>The post <a href="/news/987/">Virtual Bangkok Forum on G20 Summit</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/news/987/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Webinar on G7 Hiroshima Communique</title>
		<link>/news/983/</link>
					<comments>/news/983/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[c7Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 01:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=983</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>After the busy week of the G7 Leaders’ Summit in Hiroshima, there are two webinars organized by PEOPLES’ 20. Please join us! Time: 9 AM (New York) / 2 PM (London) / 6:30 PM (New Delhi) / 8 PM (Bangkok) / 10 PM (Seoul and Tokyo) Date: 30 and 31 May (Tuesday and Wednesday) 2023 [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/news/983/">Webinar on G7 Hiroshima Communique</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After the busy week of the G7 Leaders’ Summit in Hiroshima, there are two webinars organized by PEOPLES’ 20. Please join us!</p>
<p><strong>Time:</strong> 9 AM (New York) / 2 PM (London) / 6:30 PM (New Delhi) / 8 PM (Bangkok) / 10 PM (Seoul and Tokyo)<br />
<strong>Date:</strong> 30 and 31 May (Tuesday and Wednesday) 2023</p>
<p><strong>Zoom for Tuesday, 30 May 2023 6:30 PM Indian Time (GMT+5:30)</strong><br />
https://us06web.zoom.us/j/89200471215?pwd=T3lTZG5QUEdVMnhrdHhmZks4WENBZz09<br />
Meeting ID: 892 0047 1215 / PW: 151655</p>
<p><strong>Zoom for Wednesday, 31 May 2023 &#8211; 6:30 PM Indian Time (GMT+5:30)</strong><br />
https://us06web.zoom.us/j/88299947362?pwd=QngveVdqQm5QUTRTeUdpUXpOY0pnZz09<br />
Meeting ID: 882 9994 7362 / PW: 591299</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-984" src="/wpC7/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image-17.png" alt="" width="925" height="925" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image-17.png 925w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image-17-300x300.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image-17-768x768.png 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 925px) 100vw, 925px" /> <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-985" src="/wpC7/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image-18.png" alt="" width="925" height="926" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image-18.png 925w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image-18-300x300.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/06/image-18-768x769.png 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 925px) 100vw, 925px" /></p><p>The post <a href="/news/983/">Webinar on G7 Hiroshima Communique</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/news/983/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>[Press Release] G7 Hiroshima Summit Summed up as &#8220;Rainy&#8221; by Civil Society</title>
		<link>/news/893/</link>
					<comments>/news/893/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[c7Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 07:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=893</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>On May 21, the final day of the G7 Hiroshima Summit, Civil7 (C7), one of the official Engagement Groups of the G7, held a press conference at the Hiroshima City Youth Center. The C7 evaluated the outcomes of the G7 Hiroshima Summit, including the G7 Leaders&#8217; Declaration and related statements released on May 20, and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/news/893/">[Press Release] G7 Hiroshima Summit Summed up as “Rainy” by Civil Society</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On May 21, the final day of the G7 Hiroshima Summit, Civil7 (C7), one of the official Engagement Groups of the G7, held a press conference at the Hiroshima City Youth Center. The C7 evaluated the outcomes of the G7 Hiroshima Summit, including the G7 Leaders&#8217; Declaration and related statements released on May 20, and rated the six Working Group issues and the summit as a whole using a five-point scale: &#8220;downpour&#8221; (most disappointing), &#8220;rainy,&#8221; &#8220;cloudy,&#8221; &#8220;cloudy with a chance of sun,&#8221; and &#8220;sunny&#8221; (most satisfied).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The six Working Group issues and overall ratings are as follows</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">: &#8220;Nuclear Disarmament&#8221; &#8211; rainy; &#8220;Climate and Environmental Justice&#8221; &#8211; cloudy; &#8220;Economic Justice and Transformation&#8221; &#8211; downpour; &#8220;Global Health&#8221; &#8211; rainy; &#8220;Humanitarian Assistance and Conflict&#8221; &#8211; cloudy; and &#8220;Open and Resilient Societies&#8221; &#8211; downpour. The evaluation “as a citizen of Hiroshima&#8221; was cloudy with a chance of sun, and the &#8220;overall summary&#8221; was rainy with hope for sunny in the future.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-894" src="/wpC7/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG_3698-scaled.jpg" alt="" width="2560" height="1920" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG_3698-scaled.jpg 2560w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG_3698-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG_3698-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG_3698-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG_3698-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG_3698-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Five levels of evaluation: &#8220;downpour,&#8221; &#8220;rainy,&#8221; &#8220;cloudy,&#8221; &#8220;cloudy with a chance of sun,&#8221; and &#8220;sunny.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-895" src="/wpC7/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/天気.jpg" alt="" width="1030" height="430" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/天気.jpg 1030w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/天気-300x125.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/天気-1024x427.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/天気-768x321.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1030px) 100vw, 1030px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>C7 </b><b>Nuclear Disarmament Working Group: </b><b>Rainy (2 points out of 5)<br />
</b><b>(Akira Kawasaki, Peace Boat)</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The G7 Communiqué does not call for the abolition of nuclear weapons. The communiqué only makes excuses for not advancing nuclear disarmament, saying that a world without nuclear weapons is the &#8220;ultimate goal&#8221; and that a &#8220;realistic,&#8221; &#8220;practical,&#8221; and &#8220;responsible&#8221; approach should be taken, ensuring &#8220;undiminished security for all”. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Civil 7 recommended starting negotiations for the elimination of nuclear weapons within a set time frame, but the G7 leaders have shown no such attitude.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In their statement on nuclear disarmament, they condemn Russia&#8217;s nuclear threats but justify their own nuclear weapons saying that those are for &#8220;defensive&#8221; and &#8220;deterrence” purposes. What exactly did the G7 leaders feel when they visited Hiroshima Peace Memorial Museum and met with HIbakusha? I must say with regret that this city that experienced the nuclear catastrophe has been disgraced by senseless leaders who affirm nuclear weapons.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-896" src="/wpC7/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image2-1.jpg" alt="" width="1999" height="1500" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image2-1.jpg 1999w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image2-1-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image2-1-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image2-1-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image2-1-1536x1153.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>C7 </b><b>Climate and Environmental Justice Working Group: Cloudy (3 points out of 5)</b><b><br />
</b><b>(Risa Endo, Japan Center for a Sustainable Environment and Society (JACSES))</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">(1) It is urgently necessary to strengthen adaptation and Loss &amp; Damage measures for those who are disproportionately affected by climate change, and it is important that the G7 Hiroshima Leaders’ Communiqué includes the following:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Continuing to scale up and enhance support to strengthen the resilience of climate-vulnerable groups through enhancing climate change adaptation and climate disaster risk reduction, response and recovery, and early-warning systems</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Scaling up action and support to avert, minimize and address Loss &amp; Damage, especially for the most vulnerable countries</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Implementing the UNFCCC-COP27/CMA4 decision on Loss &amp; Damage to establish new funding arrangements, including a fund for developing countries that are particularly vulnerable to the adverse effects of climate change</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Continuing to accelerate efforts to respond to the Glasgow Climate Pact that urges developed countries to at least double their collective provision of climate finance for adaptation to developing countries from the 2019-level by 2025</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">(2)About one-third of global GHG emissions are from sources other than energy-derived CO2 emissions and it is urgently necessary to reduce other GHG emissions, together with the reduction of energy-derived CO2. emissions. Regarding enhancing the ambition and submission of NDCs, “including all GHGs” is mentioned. In addition, it is also stated that the G7 reaffirms its commitment to the Global Methane Pledge and steps up efforts to collectively reduce global anthropogenic methane emissions.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">(3)Although the support of developing countries just energy transitions and global extensions of renewable energy are included, some statements about energy such as fossil fuels are far from the outcomes recommended by our Working Group members.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-897" src="/wpC7/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image9.jpg" alt="" width="1999" height="1500" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image9.jpg 1999w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image9-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image9-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image9-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image9-1536x1153.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>C7 Economic Justice and Transformation Working Group: Downpour (1 point out of 5)</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><b>(Shoko Uchida, Pacific Asia Resource Center)</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overall, the emphasis is on &#8220;economic security&#8221; set from the perspective of the G7, rather than on solving the problems faced by developing countries, and although the text calls for &#8220;cooperation,&#8221; in reality, it is fraught with the danger of bringing division and blocs to the world. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">(1) Debt: There are no concrete commitments by the G7, only &#8220;expectations for the G20&#8221; regarding a &#8220;common framework&#8221; for debt restructuring and improving the accuracy of debt data. In particular, &#8220;enforcement of binding national laws to allow private creditors to participate in the multilateral debt restructuring process,&#8221; &#8220;multilateral negotiations at the UN,&#8221; and &#8220;debt cancellation&#8221; are not considered. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">(2) Economic Security: The goal is to decouple the supply chain of strategic goods and mineral resources such as semiconductors from China while incorporating the &#8220;Global South,&#8221; assuming China is a &#8220;market-distorting actor,&#8221; &#8220;malicious actor,&#8221; and so on. Such decoupling, however, will further impose environmental and social burdens, especially on developing countries. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">(3) Business and Human Rights: The stance on initiatives referring to international standards such as the &#8220;UN Guiding Principles on Business and Human Rights (UNGPs)&#8221; has weakened, and there is no mention of the need for mandatory human rights due diligence measures that were in place until last year.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-898" src="/wpC7/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image14.jpg" alt="" width="1999" height="1500" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image14.jpg 1999w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image14-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image14-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image14-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image14-1536x1153.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>C7 Global Health Working Group: Rainy (2 points out of 5)</b><b><br />
</b><b>(Masaki Inaba, Africa Japan Forum)</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The G7 global health process carried great expectations and efforts by many people to fully prepare for a new pandemic beyond Covid-19. However, it is unfortunate that it ended with disappointing results; one, because time has run out, and two, because of the limits and restrictions that Japan has as a country. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With regard to pandemic preparedness, a major weakness was the inability to address intellectual property rights which is one of the main causes of disparities, and mechanisms that should aim for equal access to medicine have become dependent on (industry’s) self-motivations. There is a necessity to transition from monopoly to sharing, from competition to cooperation, however, the Hiroshima Summit has missed their crucial opportunity.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although other issues were comprehensively covered, the most important demands to the G7, namely their financial and technological contributions, were not addressed, and the majority of the communique included orders to other platforms and re-statements of previous commitments. I sincerely hope for a world-oriented G7, rather than one that is preoccupied with domestic affairs.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-899" src="/wpC7/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image13.jpg" alt="" width="1999" height="1500" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image13.jpg 1999w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image13-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image13-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image13-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image13-1536x1153.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>C7 Humanitarian Assistance and Conflict Working Gr</b><strong>oup: Cloudy (3 points out of 5)</strong><b><br />
</b><b> (Yuko Shibata, Japan Platform)</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The </span>$21 billion pledge<span style="font-weight: 400;"> of support for humanitarian crises, including the food crisis, is highly commendable, as it is essential for responding to the growing humanitarian crisis. We also welcome the reference to the importance of educational opportunities and support for funds and UN agencies that cannot put education on the back burner, as well as the inclusion of efforts for disaster prevention and mitigation in line with the Sendai Framework and the strengthening of proactive actions. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overall, many of the issues that the Working Group has recommended, though mentioned, lack specificity, with no clear commitment other than the $</span>21 billion <span style="font-weight: 400;">pledged. In addition, there is no mention of &#8220;strengthening local officials and local leadership,&#8221; which is essential to the implementation of humanitarian assistance. We strongly hope that this will lead to concrete policies on how to ensure access to humanitarian assistance and protection, in order to make progress in addressing serious humanitarian assistance system challenges.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-902" src="/wpC7/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image4.jpg" alt="" width="1999" height="1500" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image4.jpg 1999w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image4-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image4-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image4-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image4-1536x1153.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>C7 Open and Resilient Societies Working Group: Downpour (1 point out of 5)</b><b><br />
</b><b>(Hirotaka Koike, Greenpeace Japan)</b></p>
<p>G7&#8217;s failure to show a strong commitment to civic space and open society is proof of double standards &#8211; claiming to promote the rule of law and democracy on the one hand and, on the other hand, providing little to no commitment to improving the dire situation of shrinking civic space, increased limitation to freedom of expression and of academia, and imprisonment of whistleblowers. While Japan had an opportunity to simply issue similar statements to at least show its commitment to open and resilient democracies, like Elmau and Cornwall summits, they did not show any political will to address these issues. Where democracy was concerned, although the importance of democracy was noted, the discussion was mostly about information warfare with other countries, which neglects its own control and limits on freedom of expression happening within G7. On migration, this is a human-rights-violating paragraph. Almost half of it is about irregular migrants and organised crime, without suggesting any ways to improve the harsh conditions migrants are currently in. There has been no improvement in civic engagement in the International Media Centre, and NGOs have been pushed out and even the NGO activity schedule board at the IMC has been taken down. The summit statement states that the G7 is “committed to listening to and supporting civil society organisations.” We look forward to G7 walking the talk.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-903" src="/wpC7/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image5.jpg" alt="" width="1999" height="1500" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image5.jpg 1999w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image5-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image5-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image5-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image5-1536x1153.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>&lt;Overall Evaluation&gt; </b></p>
<p><b>G7 Hiroshima Summit Seen from the Perspective of Civil Society in Hiroshima: Cloudy With a Chance of Sun (4 out of 5)<br />
</b><b>(Hiroki Matsubara, Hiroshima NPO Center)</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a citizen of Hiroshima, I feel that holding the G7 Summit in Hiroshima was of great significance. In this sense, I would like to show my gratitude to Prime Minister Fumio Kishida who has served as the G7 President &#8211; it can be valued that the visit to the Peace Memorial Park of G7 leaders including nuclear power was realized. I am also grateful for my fellow civil society members, citizens of Hiroshima who have worked together, the media who brought our voice to the governments and to the world, and the Ministry of Foreign Affairs who supported our activities.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I do not believe that anyone knows exactly what the proper outcome of the G7 Summit is. However, from the perspective of civil society, I believe that every one of us did have something to learn and realize through the G7 Hiroshima Summit. In other words, it was a precious opportunity for us to learn about international social issues and diversity.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a member of the C7 Steering Committee, I strongly insist that civil society has something that we only can do to resolve. It bears great importance that those involved in politics and civil societies cooperate with each other. With such a background, nevertheless, the latest G7 Leaders’ Declaration seemed only for politics and excludes civil society. Honestly speaking, I cannot help but think for what purpose and outcome the G7 Summit is being held, if the citizens&#8217; voice is not heard.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After the Summit is over, as a citizen of Hiroshima and as a member of an NGO, I will be continuously working towards the realization of a world without nuclear weapons and a sustainable society, together with civil society all across the globe.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-904" src="/wpC7/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image1.jpg" alt="" width="1999" height="1500" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image1.jpg 1999w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image1-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image1-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image1-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image1-1536x1153.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Summary: Evaluation: Rain (Hopefully sunny, at least cloudy)<br />
</b><b> (Mariko Kinai, World Vision Japan) </b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The six C7 Working Groups gave poor ratings to the G7 summit declaration. While the specific reasons for this differ from one Working Group to another, the overall assessment is “2” (rain) on a scale of 5 and we have to say that the summit declaration does not adequately nor sufficiently reflect the perspectives of citizens.</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">The role of the C7 along with other engagement groups is to provide perspectives that the &#8216;G&#8217; (governments) do not have. C7, as has been doing so far, is continuously asking whether the policies of the seven countries will truly lead to the realization of the &#8216;society where no one is left behind&#8217; that the SDGs aim to achieve. By expanding and deepening this continuous engagement process, we hope that our weather forecast will turn from “rainy” to “sunny”, or at least become cloudy.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-900" src="/wpC7/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image8.jpg" alt="" width="1999" height="1500" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image8.jpg 1999w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image8-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image8-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image8-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image8-1536x1153.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">END</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Related Information</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The full text of the C7 Communiqué is available from<br />
</span><a href="/wpC7/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/C7_communique2023_0412.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">/wpC7/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/C7_communique2023_0412.pdf</span></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>About the C7 </b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The G7 has its official Engagement Groups, which engage in policy dialogue and make recommendations to influence the G7 outcome document on areas of interest. The Civil7 (C7) is one of these Engagement Groups and is organized by civil society. Each year, civil society in the presiding country, in collaboration with civil society not only from G7 countries but also from G20 countries and the Global South, formulates and disseminates recommendations to the G7. For more information, please visit the C7 website (in English): </span><a href="/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">/</span></a></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-905" src="/wpC7/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image7.png" alt="" width="189" height="158" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image7.png 650w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image7-300x250.png 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 189px) 100vw, 189px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>About Japan Civil Society Coalition on G7 2023</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Japan Civil Society Coalition on G7 2023 is a platform to encourage the G7 governments to ensure that the G7 Leaders&#8217; Summit and related ministerial meetings to be held in Hiroshima in 2023 reflect the voices of civil society and to contribute to the realization of the 2030 Agenda. For more information on the coalition, please visit the following:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Japan Civil Society Coalition on G7 2023 website: </span><a href="https://g7-cso-coalition-japan-2023.mystrikingly.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://g7-cso-coalition-japan-2023.mystrikingly.com/</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> 　</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Twitter: </span><a href="https://twitter.com/g7cso2023"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://twitter.com/g7cso2023</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> 　  </span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Instagram: </span><a href="https://www.instagram.com/g7cso2023"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.instagram.com/g7cso2023</span></a></li>
</ul><p>The post <a href="/news/893/">[Press Release] G7 Hiroshima Summit Summed up as “Rainy” by Civil Society</a> first appeared on <a href="">CIVIL SOCIETY 7 - 2023 JAPAN</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/news/893/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
